And run into our enemy, and
it will fly off into the distance.
Now the problem here is
that our power-up basically
lasts forever, and
that's not entirely fair.
So we're actually going
to add a timer in so
that we can remove this
power-up at a certain time.
In our player controller
script, we're going
to go down underneath our on-trigger-enter,
and we're going to create a new method.
So this method is going
to be a little strange.
It's called an iInumerator.
You might notice that after
adding the iInumerator type,
your IDE highlights it with
a red squiggly error line.
If you check Unity's console, you'll likely
see an error message saying the type or
namespace name
iInumerator could not be found.
Are you missing a using
directive or an assembly reference?
There's no need to worry,
however, because this is a simple fix.
The issue here is that we're
missing a using directive.
In C#, using directives
are lines at the beginning
of a script that specify which name
spaces your code needs access to.
So adding the right
using statement lets your
code know where to look for
the type that you're trying to use.
In this case, we need to add the
using system.collection directive.
So go ahead and add
that line at the top of your
script, along with the
other using statement.
Once you've added it, the error
in your IDE should disappear.
Once you save your script,
then return to Unity, you'll
see that the console error
has been resolved as well.
With that out of the way, let's jump
back into working with Cobra Teens.
That will call our power
up countdown routine.
Now an iInumerator is something in
programming and C# known as an interface.
In this case, it's not entirely necessary
to go into how it works or what it does, but
it is very helpful to
be able to do certain
things like enable a countdown
timer outside of our update loop.
The way we're able to use this countdown
timer outside of our update loop is through
use of something called Cobra Teens that
will be able to run with a function called
wait for seconds.
Now to be able to
make this entire process
work, we actually need
to use a keyword called
yield, and so this will
actually enable us to
run this timer in a place
outside of our update loop.
So if we type yield, return, new, and
we're creating a new wait for seconds.
And we'll wait for, let's call
it a seven or so seconds.
So now our iInumerator is going to create a
new thread outside of our update loop, and
it will use the wait
for seconds method to
wait for seven seconds
before we do something.
Now, it'll wait for seven seconds, and then
eventually once that timer is stopped, we
can set our has power up to false, and then
we're able to reset our player's state back
to before they picked up the power up.
Now in order to actually use this method,
we then need to use another method, which
will put inside of our
on trigger enter in our
if statement, because
that's when the players
picked up the power
up, we're going to start
a co routine, which
will actually start that
thread, start that loop
outside of our update method.
And then we call our
power up countdown routine.
So it'll start another
thread, use the power
up countdown routine,
wait for seven seconds,
set our power up to false, and then
we'll be back to the way we started.
So then we go in our
game, let's take a look
at the player and just
watch the has power
up variable, watch
that checkbox, pick up
the power up, enemy goes away, and
eventually has power up should turn off.
There you go.
So what you're going to do in your player
controller script, you're going to add this
line of code to create
an I enumerator method.
In this I enumerator method, make sure
to use yield return new wait for seconds.
That way it waits for a
certain amount of time
before it actually does this
sets our power up to false.
And then in our on trigger enter, one we've
picked up a power up, we start a co routine
and use our power up countdown
routine to start that countdown timer.
Now it's your turn.